<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Service Computing | Yifei Liu</title>
    <link>/tags/service-computing/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/service-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Service Computing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 Created by Yifei Liu</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hudf018ff48b348cd4b6bccc683f271f37_64216_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Service Computing</title>
      <link>/tags/service-computing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Network Reasoning</title>
      <link>/project/bayesiannetwork-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/bayesiannetwork-proj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the domain of service-oriented computing, it is crucial to suggest not only individual atomic services but also a suite of interrelated services that align with users&amp;rsquo; Quality of Service (QoS) expectations. To optimize the organization and recommendation of web services, our approach employs a three-tiered Bayesian network structure learning process. This process is designed to formulate a directed acyclic graph (network) and then engages in parameter learning to deduce the conditional probabilities across all network nodes. Our utilization of the Bayesian network, known for its adept handling of service correlations, represents a more appropriate choice for recommending interconnected services when compared to alternative methods. We conducted thorough experiments to validate our proposed method, demonstrating its capabilities and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;b&gt;My role: I worked on the experiments of Bayesian Network Reasoning for web service recommendation and had tested different sampling (e.g., Gibbs sampling, MCMC) and inference (e.g., variable elimination, junction tree) algorithms for Bayesian network together with various searching methods (e.g., greedy search, hill climbing, and K2 algorithm).&lt;/b&gt; --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
